Aviel Cohanian

Full Stack | Frontend Web Developer

Tel: 050-3431443 • Email: avielcohanian@gmail.com • LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/aviel-cohanian

Summary

I am a full Stack Web Developer, graduated from Coding academy. I have experience in writing single-page-applications using the latest WEB technologies such as Vue.js, React.js, Angular, JavaScript (ES5, Es6) ...
I enjoy reflecting on problems and paradoxes. Hard worker, passionate about solving challenges, focusing on problem solving and detailed orientation, self-learner, team player with strong communication skills.

Checkout my final project at Coding Academy: Trelix, inspired by Trello. You can see more projects in my Github.

Tech skills:

- Programming in modern JavaScript (ES5, ES6), building a full scale web app.
- JS Frameworks and state Management: **Vue**(Vuex), **Angular**(Ngrx), **React**(Hooks, Redux).
- Building multi Page Applications.
- HTML5, CSS3 and SASS, From Photoshop to a live page, Responsive design and "mobile first".
- Bootstrap and ¡Query.
- Server side, APIs and REST with Node.JS, Firebase.
- Database management with MongoDb and SQL.

Personal-Projects (build outside of my studies in the bootcamp):

- Spotifo: inspired by the great Spotify, Spotifo was build with ReactJs (Hooks) & Node.js. Link: Spotifo
- Portfolio: Build with Vue.js(routes, scss, font-awesome...) Link: <u>Portfolio</u>
- MisterBitcoin: Build with ReactJs (Hooks) & Firebase Link: MisterBit

Professional Experience:

Combat Solider, Classified Unit in the Air Force, (Rank: Staff Sergeant), IDF

2018 - 2021

- Making important decisions under pressure.
- The service demanded leading a team of soldiers.
- Working with variety of people.
- The Military Service included Persistence, Time management, Responsibility, Teamwork.

Sales person, Isracard | 2017 - 2018

- Working in a fast-paced environment.
- Dealing with inquiries E2E.
- Marketing products while dealing with customers.

Education:

Udemy 2022, Modern React with Redux & Advanced React and Redux.

Coding Academy (2021) | Full Stack Web Coding Bootcamp.

Bar ilan High School, Tel-Aviv (2013 – 2018) | Majors: Computer and Chemistry.